

 [
    {
      "question": " The ruling class",
      "choice1": "patrician",
      "choice2": "plebeian",
      "choice3": "consul",
      "choice4": "veto",
      "answer": 1
    },
    {
      "question": "Ordinary citizens",
      "choice1": "patrician",
      "choice2": "plebeian",
      "choice3": "consul",
      "choice4": "veto",
      "answer": 2
    },
    {
      "question": "head of government, usually",
      "choice1": "patrician",
      "choice2": "plebeian",
      "choice3": "consul",
      "choice4": "veto",
      "answer": 3
    },
    {
      "question": "to reject",
     "choice1": "patrician",
      "choice2": "plebeian",
      "choice3": "consul",
      "choice4": "veto",
      "answer": 4
    },
    {
      "question": "government officials who interpret the law and serve as judges",
      "choice1": "praetor",
      "choice2": "tribune",
      "choice3": "dictator",
      "choice4": "civic duty ",
      "answer": 1
    },
    {
      "question": "an elect official who protects the rights of ordinary citizens",
      "choice1": "praetor",
      "choice2": "tribune",
      "choice3": "dictator",
      "choice4": "civic duty ",
      "answer": 2
    },
    {
      "question": "A person granted absolute power",
      "choice1": "praetor",
      "choice2": "tribune",
      "choice3": "dictator",
      "choice4": "civic duty ",
      "answer": 3
    },
    {
      "question": "The idea that citizens have a responsibility to help their country",
     "choice1": "praetor",
      "choice2": "tribune",
      "choice3": "dictator",
      "choice4": "civic duty ",
      "answer": 4
    },
    {
      "question": "The ____________ was the ruling class on top officials of the Roman Republic",
      "choice1": "Patricians",
      "choice2": "Carthage.",
      "choice3": " twelve tables",
      "choice4": "cincinnatus",
      "answer": 1
    },
    {
      "question": "Rome fought ___________ in the punic wars.",
      "choice1": "Patricians",
      "choice2": "Carthage.",
      "choice3": " twelve tables",
      "choice4": "cincinnatus",
      "answer": 2
    },
    {
      "question": "The ____________ was Rome's first code of laws.",
      "choice1": "Patricians",
      "choice2": "Carthage.",
      "choice3": " twelve tables",
      "choice4": "cincinnatus",
      "answer": 3
    },
    {
      "question": "_____________ was a famous Roman dictator.",
      "choice1": "Patricians",
      "choice2": "Carthage.",
      "choice3": " twelve tables",
      "choice4": "cincinnatus",
      "answer": 4
    },
    {
      "question": "The _____________ went on strike to protest that they had no power in the government.",
      "choice1": "Patricians",
      "choice2": "Carthage.",
      "choice3": " twelve tables",
      "choice4": "plebeians",
      "answer": 4
    }  
  ]
